Muhammed Ali DİNÇ

18.02.1985 | Residency permit B (Turkey) | Married, 3 children 8853 Lachen, Switzerland malidinc@windowslive.com | +41 77 472 11 86

GitHub | LinkedIn



SUMMARY

I have a bachelor's degree in Systems Engineering and a master's degree in Organizational Development, and after serving as a military officer for 10 years, I have dedicated myself to DevOps/Cloud Engineering. In 2020, I was forced to relocate my family Switzerland because of political situation and injustices in Turkey. Through 14 months of Clarusway Bootcamp, I have gained a deep understanding of DevOps and Cloud Technology. Over the past 2 years, I've completed over 60 hands-on trainings and 10 projects, as well as obtained certificates in AWS, Azure, Kubernetes, and Terraform. I've spent 81 hours practicing to deploy Terraform-, Docker- and Kubernetes-based workloads, and configure them on the CLI with Linux. Moreover, I have a strong growth mindset combined with open-mindedness and determination that enables me to efficiently learn new skills and adapt to new environments. I'm currently looking for hybrid or remote internship that would allow me to gain work experience in Cloud/DevOps field.

WORK EXPERIENCE

08/2019 - 04/2020

Internet Ads Assessor (remote), Lionbridge, Ireland

- Reviewing the language used in ads by examining grammar, tone cultural relevance (English content moderator)
- Provide feedback and analysis on ads found in search engine results
- Reviewing online ads to improve their content, quality, and layout

11/2016 - 07/2018

Operations and Training Officer, Turkish Land Forces, Turkey

- Training planning and coordinating military events across multiple troops
- Preparing and analyzing training results to provide feedback and create insight for future pieces of training
- Analyzing intelligence reports and providing immediate notice to the troops
- Performing presentations and making speeches
- Prepare troops for the audits of top executives

08/2011 - 11/2016

Company Leader, Turkish Military Academy, Turkey

- Responsible for 123 Cadets
- Individual meeting with cadets on a regular basis to assess and motivate them to maintain their military, sports and academical success
- Planning sports and military training
- Teach military concepts and basic combat skills
- Planning and joining summer camps on a terrain
- Designing relevant scenarios to develop their judgment abilities under compelling circumstances (right decision making in less-time)

08/2009 - 08/2011 Squad Leader, Turkish Land Forces, Turkey

• Responsible for 17 subordinates

- Preparing correspondence and reports, verifying personnel data
- Oversaw teams planning, implementing and realigning field and base operational strategies
- Integrated intelligence activities into other military operations, plans and programs

09/2008 - 07/2009 Trainee, Turkish Land Forces, Turkey, conscripted,

- Attended Officer Leadership Training
- Basic infantry skills
- Military concepts and tactics

EDUCATION & FURTHER EDUCATION

05/2023 03/2023 - 06/2023	CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator, Linux Foundation
	Clarusway DevOps Bootcamp (online), USA
04/2023	Hashicorp Certified: Terraform Associate (003)
08/2022	Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
02/2022	DevOps and Build Automation with Python, Learnquest
01/2022	Linux Server Management and Security, Colorado University, Coursera
01/2022	IBM Cybersecurity Analyst, Coursera
02/2021	AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate
12/2020	Container Orchestration Using Kubernetes, Coursera
09/2020	The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking, Coursera, Google
08/2020	Python Data Structures, Michigan University
05/2020 - 02/2021	Clarusway IT Bootcamp, Virginia 2020, basics of AWS/DevOps Engineering: computer fundamentals, AWS and DevOps
2013 - 2019	Master Program in Organisational Development, Ankara Yildirim Beyazit University, Turkey
2004 - 2008	Bachelor's degree in System Engineering, National Defence Academy, Ankara, Turkey

LANGUAGES

English	Fluent (C1)
German	Intermediate (B2)
Turkish	Native

HOBBIES

Table tennis, Chess, Go and Abalone, Research, meeting with friends

REFERENCES

Available upon request